Register to The Quincy Porter Papers
Yale University Music Library
Quincy Porter Papers
1897-1975
MSS 15
Yale University Music Library
43
(66 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the American composer Quincy Porter (1897-1966)
Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to qualified researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Quincy Porter Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Lois Porter in 1972.
Arrangement
In 12 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Programs. III. Newspaper clippings. IV. Biographical & analytical notes V. Classroom materials. VI. Published articles and books. VII. Photographs. VIII. Medals. IX. Scrapbooks. X. Porter's works. XI. Works copied or arranged by Porter. XII. Manuscript & photocopy works of other composers.
Scope and Contents
The Quincy Porter Papers contain the manuscript scores and sketches of Porter's musical compositions, including 2 symphonies, 9 string quartets, and other major compositions and smaller pieces. The Papers also include music copied or arranged by Porter. The correspondence contains letters to and from Porter and other individuals, publishers, performing organizations, and schools and universities. Porter's life and work are further documented by: programs and newspaper clippings; published articles and books; photographs; medals; and scrapbooks.
Biographical / Historical
Quincy Porter was born in New Haven, Connecticut in 1897. He attended Yale University as a student of Horatio Parker. After graduating from there his studies carried him to Paris, New York, and Cleveland, and his teachers included Vincent d'Indy and Ernest Bloch. As a composer and teacher himself, Porter held positions at the Cleveland Institute, Vassar College, and the New England Conservatory - where he became its director in 1942 - before returning to Yale in 1946 as professor of music. He concluded his professional career there, serving as Master of Pierson College and Battell Professor of Music Theory. He died in Bethany, Connecticut on November 12, 1966.
Included on his list of many honors are the Coolidge Medal (1943) and the Pulitzer Prize for musical composition, awarded in 1954 for his Concerto Concertante for two pianos and orchestra.
Porter was actively involved in musical activities on the national level, as a glance at the register which follows will point out. Included in this collection is a wealth of correspondence dealing with his involvement in the American Composers Alliance, the National Institute of Arts & Letters, the American Music Center, and many other organizations and societies which concerned themselves with the musical developments of this century. Porter also played a major role in the organization of the musical sessions held at the Yaddo grounds located in Saratoga Springs, New York, and the large body of Yaddo correspondence contained in this collection provides something of the flavor of the events there during the late '30s.
Composers -- Correspondence; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Sonatas (Violin and piano) -- Scores and parts; Songs; String quartets -- Scores and parts; Symphonies -- Scores; Archer, Violet, 1913-2000; Bain, Wilfred C. (Wilfred Conwell), 1908-1997; Bales, Richard, 1915-1998; Barber, Samuel, 1910-1981; Barrows, John, 1913-1974; Bartholomew, Marshall, 1885-1978; Baumgartner, H. Leroy (Hope Leroy), 1891-1969; Beeson, Jack, 1921-2010; Bennett, Robert Russell, 1894-1981; Beyer, Johanna Magdalena, 1888-1944; Binkerd, Gordon, 1916-2003; Bloch, Ernest, 1880-1959; Boulanger, Nadia, 1887-1979; Brieff, Frank; Brunswick, Mark; Chasins, Abram, 1903-1987; Childs, Barney, 1926-2000; Clarke, Henry Leland, 1907-1992; Coffin, William Sloane, Jr., 1924-2006; Cohn, Arthur, 1910-1998; Converse, F. S. (Frederick Shepherd), 1871-1940; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965; Creston, Paul, 1906-1985; Delaney, Robert Mills, 1903-1956; Diamond, David, 1915-2005; Dickinson, George Sherman, 1888-1964; Doktor, Paul, 1919-1989; Donovan, Richard, 1891-1970; Edmunds, John, 1913-1986; Elkus, Jonathan, 1931-; Elwell, Herbert, 1898-1974; Etler, Alvin, 1913-1973; Fairchild, Blair, 1877-1933; Fennell, Frederick, 1914-2004; Fetler, Paul; Fiedler, Arthur, 1894-1979; Finney, Ross Lee, 1906-1997; Forte, Allen, 1926-2014; Freed, Isadore, 1900-1960; French, Richard F. (Richard Frederic), 1915-2001; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963; Gilman, Lawrence, 1878-1939; Glanville-Hicks, Peggy, 1912-1990; Goeb, Roger, 1914-1997; Goodrich, Wallace, 1871-1952; Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979; Helm, Everett, 1913-1999; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963; Jacobi, Frederick, 1891-1952; James, Philip, 1890-1975; Kaufman, Louis, 1905-1994; Kilpatrick, Jack Frederick; Kirkpatrick, Ralph, 1911-1984; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Kroll, William, 1901-1980; La Montaine, John, 1920-2013; Labunski, Felix, 1892-1979; Layton, Billy Jim, 1924-2004; Lewin, Frank; Lockwood, Normand, 1906-2002; Lopatnikoff, Nikolai, 1903-1976; Lucier, Alvin, 1931-; Luening, Otto, 1900-1996; McKay, George Frederick, 1899-1970; McKinley, Carl, 1895-1966; Moore, Douglas, 1893-1969; Morris, Harold, 1890-1964; Noss, Luther, 1907-1995; Palmer, Robert, 1915-2010; Parisot, Aldo, 1921-; Partch, Harry, 1901-1974; Pisk, Paul Amadeus, 1893-1990; Porter, Lois; Porter, Quincy, 1897-1966; Primrose, William, 1904-1982; Saminsky, Lazare, 1882-1959; Scherchen, Hermann, 1891-1966; Schuman, William, 1910-1992; Shaw, Artie, 1910-2004; Shaw, Robert, 1916-1999; Shepherd, Arthur, 1880-1958; Shulman, Alan, 1915-2002; Siegmeister, Elie, 1909-1991; Sims, Ezra, 1928-2015; Skinner, Ernest M.; Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995; Smith, Carleton Sprague, 1905-1994; Somary, Johannes, 1935-2011; Stern, Blake; Stevens, Halsey, 1908-1989; Stoessel, Albert, 1894-1943; Strickland, William, 1914-1991; Strunk, W. Oliver (William Oliver), 1901-1980; Tangeman, Robert, 1910-1964; Thompson, Randall, 1899-1984; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989; Tulan, Fred; Tuthill, Burnet, 1888-1982; Wagner, Joseph, 1900-1974; Webster, Beveridge, 1908-1999; Whitmer, T. Carl (Thomas Carl), 1873-1959; Wigglesworth, Frank, 1918-1996; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Wyner, Yehudi, 1929-; American Composers Alliance; Yale School of Music; Yaddo Festival (Saratoga Springs, N.Y.)
- Correspondence, Series I
  General
  1897-1975 -- 18 Boxes
  An attempt has been made to arrange the correspondence into logical subdivisions according to subject matter and content, so as to aid the researcher in dealing with the rather large number of items in this series. This manner of organization hopefully preserves much of Porter's own attitude toward his correspondence, as many of these subdivisions were already in existence in the collection as he left it. (The Pulitzer Prize congratulatory letters, for example, were completely intact as a unit.) Because of Porter's special association with Yale in the capacity of a college master as well as faculty member, category (I) has been created to include correspondence dealing specifically with Pierson College or the Yale School of Music. Also included here are letters of congratulation from outside the Yale comunity which were addressed to Porter upon his appointment as master.
  Within the subject-oriented categories--such as (C) Concerning Publication--letters to and from Porter have been grouped together and listed alphabetically by the name of the company, organization, etc., while the letters in section A (general) have been subdivided into those written to Porter and those written by Porter.
  Cross references: Cross references have been provided throughout the correspondence to assist the researcher in locating specific correspondence. It should be noted that references have not been provided for letters falling into two categories:
  (B) Congratulatory letters-Pulitzer Prize
  (K) Lois Porter's correspondence
  Since these categories contain letters from persons closely associated with Porter in his various musical activities, it would seem rather redundant to provide individual references for these sections.
  (scrapbook): The indication (scrapbook) which appears after many entries in the register is an explanation of the fact that what appears in the correspondence files is a photocopy of the original, the original being found in one of the several scrapbooks (series IX). Information as to the specific location-including page number in scrapbook--of the original has been notated on each of the photocopies.
  - General Correspondence, I.A
    - To Porter, from Individuals, I.A.1
      - Acker, Ernest and Geraldine (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1938 Apr 3 -- telegram (scrapbook)
      - Adkins, Mrs. Archibald W. (Box 1, Folder 1)
        No year May 10 -- autograph letter
      - Adkins, Mr. & Mrs. Archibald W. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Agrafiotis, Sandy (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1965 May 10 -- autograph letter signed
      - Albritton, Sherry (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1964 Jul 29 -- autograph letter signed
      - Aliferis, James (Box 1, Folder 1)
        See: New England Conservatory of Music
      - Allen, Philip R. (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1946 Dec 31 -- typed letter signed
      - Altwater, Hugh (Box 1, Folder 1)
        No date [c.1950?] -- autograph letter signed
      - Ames, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 1)
        See: Yaddo
      - [Andrady, H.M.?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
        No date -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Angell, Kay (Box 1, Folder 1)
        See: Yale
      - Antal, Jeno (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1942 Jun 3 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Archer, Violet (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1961 Apr 9 -- autograph letter signed
      - Arnold, Harold S. (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1950 Jun 4 -- typed letter signed
      - Autori, Franco (Box 1, Folder 1)
        No date -- card (scrapbook)
      - Bacon, Ernst (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Bailey, Parker (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1929-1958 -- 4 typed letters signed (1-scrapbook)
        See also: Society for the Publication of American Music
      - Bailly, Louis (Box 1, Folder 1)
        See: Josephine Dickey
      - Bain, Wilfred C. (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1947-1962 -- 2 typed letters signed
        [1947, summer] -- telegram
      - Balaban, Emanuel (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1957 Mar 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Baldwin, Cordelia J. (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1950 Apr 24 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Baldwin, Sherman (Box 1, Folder 1)
        1958 Dec 19 -- typed letter signed
      - Bales, Richard (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1944-1947 -- 4 typed letters signed (1-scrapbook)
      - Barber, Samuel (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1962 May 19 -- typed letter signed
      - Barron, Dolores (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1947 Feb 5 -- typed letter signed
      - Barrows, John (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1938 -- 2 autograph letters signed
        1939 May 12 -- typed letter signed
        No year Feb 21 -- card (scrapbook)
        See also: Yaddo
      - Bartholomew, Marshall (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1961 Jan 27 -- typed letter signed
      - Bartlett, E.L. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1962 Apr 19 -- typed letter signed
      - Bauer, Karl F. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        See: Associated Music Publishers, Inc.
      - Bauer, Marion (Box 1, Folder 2)
        See: Society for the Publication of American Music
      - Baumgartner, Hope Leroy (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Becker, Frank S. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1938 Oct 25 -- typed letter signed
      - Bedell, Walter R. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1936 Oct 3 -- typed letter signed
      - Beeson, Jack (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1964 May 26 -- typed letter signed
        See also: Columbia University. Alice M. Ditson Fund
      - Bennett, Robert Russell (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1959 Feb 28 -- typed letter signed
      - [Berckenon, ?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1936 Oct 14 -- autograph letter signed
      - Berger, Carl (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1965 Jul 28 -- typed letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Berkowitz, Lois (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1966 Feb 18 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Berry, F.F. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1959 Jun 20 -- typed letter signed
      - Bestor, Dorothea N. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        No year Aug 11 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Betti, Adolfo (Box 1, Folder 2)
        [1925] -- 3 autograph letters signed (2-scrapbook)
      - Beyer, Johanna M. (Box 1, Folder 2)
        1940 Mar 17 -- typed letter signed
      - [Biner, Jean ?] (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1953 May 14 -- autograph letter signed
      - Binkerd, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1962 Dec 3 -- typed letter signed
      - Bittner, Francis W. (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1958 Jun 3 -- typed letter signed
      - Blaisdell, Paul C. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bloch, Ernest (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1921 Aug 26 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Bloom, Donna (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1960 Jan 19 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Boatwright, Howard (family) (Box 1, Folder 3)
        See: Lois Porter's Correspondence
      - Bodenhorn, Aaron (Box 1, Folder 3)
        No date -- 2 autograph letters signed
      - Boepple, Paul (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1935 May 21 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Bolck, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1963 Jun 19 -- typed letter signed
      - Border, Fred and Minner (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Boulanger, Nadia (Box 1, Folder 3)
        No date -- 3 autograph letters signed (scrapbook), card
      - Boyd, Lorine Ellsworth (Box 1, Folder 3)
        1938 Mar 28 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Bramer, Ben (Box 1, Folder 4)
        No date -- autograph letter signed
      - [Brandai, José Vieira] (Box 1, Folder 4)
        No date -- typed letter signed
      - Brant, Henry (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Breton, Ruth (Box 1, Folder 4)
        No year Sep 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Breul, Sue (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1939 May 12 -- card
      - Bricken, Carl (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1942 May 14 -- typed letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Brieff, Frank. (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1953 Mar 19 -- autograph letter signed
        See also: Yale
      - Broder, Nathan (Box 1, Folder 4)
        See: The Musical Quarterly
      - Bronke, Louise (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1938 Apr 3 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Brown, Mrs. [mother-in-law] (Box 1, Folder 4)
        [1938] -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Browne, Robert (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1961 Mar 23 -- autograph letter signed
      - Brunswick, Mark (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1938 -- 2 typed letters signed
        See also: International Society for Contemporary Music
      - Buchanan, Carl (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1939 Jan 7 -- typed letter signed
      - Bunts, Alec (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1959 Jun 29 -- typed letter signed
      - Burr, Caroline Lynette (Box 1, Folder 4)
        [1946?] Sep 20 -- autograph letter signed
      - Buxton, Frances (Box 1, Folder 4)
        1948 Mar 4 -- typed letter signed
      - Cannon, Beekman (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1960 Mar 13 -- autograph letter signed
        See also: New Haven Symphony
      - Caplan, Lewis E. (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1964 Apr 6 -- typed letter signed
      - Cardew, Bruce (Box 1, Folder 5)
        No year Apr 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Carlson, Algot J. (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1950 Jan 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Carlucci, Joseph B. (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1947 Jul 16 -- typed letter signed
      - Carnahan, Anne (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carter, Alan (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1958 Apr 16 -- typed letter signed
      - Chaitman, Arnold (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1959 Feb 1 -- typed letter signed
      - Chapman, R.E. (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1950 Jan 30 -- typed letter signed
      - Chasins, Abram (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1938; 1947 -- 3 typed letters signed (1-scrapbook)
      - Childs, Barney (Box 1, Folder 5)
        See also: American Composers Alliance
      - Christ-Janer, Albert (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1956-1957 -- 3 typed letters signed (1-scrapbook)
      - Churchill, Dorothy (Box 1, Folder 5)
        1947 May 14 -- typed letter signed
      - Claflin, Avery (Box 1, Folder 5)
        See: Composers Recordings, Inc.; American Composers Alliance
      - Clark, Gertrude (Box 1, Folder 6)
        [1938 Apr] -- telegram (scrapbook)
      - Clarke, Henry Leland (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1947 Jul 14 -- typed letter signed
      - Cleveland, Alice Erdman (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1938 Sep 30 -- autograph letter signed
      - Clifton, Chalmers (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1937-1963 -- 5 autograph letters signed
        1938 Mar 14 -- typed letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Clifton, Wanda B. (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1937 -- 3 autograph letters signed (1-scrapbook)
      - Cobb, Dan (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1960 Mar 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Coeller, Mary M. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Coffin, Catherine (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Coffin, Hannah B. (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1940 May 7 -- typed letter signed
      - Coffin, William Sloane (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - [Cohan, Hans and Hilda ?] (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cohn, Arthur (Box 1, Folder 6)
        1938 Apr 19 -- autograph letter signed
      - Cohu, Eleanor Foster (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Coker, Wilson William (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1964 Dec 20 -- autograph letter signed
        1958-1964 -- 6 typed letters signed
      - Colum, Padraic (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1964 -- 2 typed letters signed
      - Conant, Harriet (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1938 Sep 6 -- autograph letter signed
      - Conner, Kathryn N. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Contiguglia, John (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1959-1961 -- 3 autograph letters signed
      - Converse, Frederick S. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Cooke, Judd (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1938 Aug 29 -- autograph letter signed
      - Cooley, Carlton (Box 1, Folder 7)
        No year Mar 19 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Coolidge, Arlan (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1945 Mar 14 -- autograph letter signed
      - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1943 -- 2 typed letters signed (scrapbook)
      - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1937 Jan 19 -- telegram (scrapbook)
      - Cooper, James Wayne (Box 1, Folder 7)
        1963 Apr 25 -- autograph letter signed
      - [Copland, Aaron ?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1938 Oct 6 -- autograph letter signed
      - Copland, Aaron (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1959 Dec 3 -- typed letter signed
        See also: Yaddo; National Institute of Arts & Letters
      - [Copland, Aaron ?] (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1938 Oct 28 -- card
      - Corelli, Keith (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1928 Nov 20 -- autograph letter signed
      - Corzine, Cordi (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1939 Aug 8 -- typed letter signed
      - Cowell, Henry (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1938-1946 -- 2 typed letters signed
        See also: New School for Social Research; Johanna M. Beyer
      - Creston, Paul (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1939 Feb 20 -- autograph letter signed
        1939 -- 2 typed letters signed
        1939 Dec 16 -- telegram (scrapbook)
      - Cushman, Grace N. (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1956 Jul 28 -- autograph letter signed
      - Daggett, Stanley (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1962 Jul 7 -- typed letter signed
      - Dana, Richard H. (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1957-1965 -- 2 typed letters signed
        See also: Music Press, Inc.
      - Daniel, Minna Lederman (Box 1, Folder 8)
        See: League of Composers
      - Daniel, Oliver (Box 1, Folder 8)
        See: Broadcast Music, Inc.; Associated Music Publishers, Inc.; American Composers Alliance
      - Danks, Harry (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1952 Dec 5 -- autograph letter signed
        1952-1954 -- 5 typed letters signed
      - Darby, Doris S. (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1958 Apr 19 -- typed letter signed
      - Darling, Jock (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - D'Arms, Edward F. (Box 1, Folder 8)
        1963 Dec 1 -- autograph letter signed
        1937-1947; 1964 -- 5 typed letters signed
        See also: Ford Foundation
      - [Davidson, Duane ?] (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1960 -- 2 autograph letter signed
        [1960?] -- typed letter signed
      - Davison, John (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1965 Sep 2 -- autograph letter signed
      - Delaney, Robert (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1938-1950 -- 6 autograph letters signed (1-scrapbook)
        1939 Mar 25 -- typed letter signed
        See also: Robert Delaney to Dr. Goodrich (folder 37)
      - Dello Joio, Norman (Box 1, Folder 9)
        See: Juilliard School of Music; Century Association
      - De Loache, Benjamin (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Diamond, David (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1939 Sep 21 -- typed letter signed
      - Dickey, Josephine (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1939 Jul 26 -- typed letter signed
      - Dickinson, G.S. (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1938-1959 -- 5 typed letters signed
      - Diemer, Frederick (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1949 Jun 17 -- autograph letter signed
      - Diers, Ann (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1965 Feb 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Dietrich, Dan (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Dittler, Herbert (Box 1, Folder 9)
        1941 Dec 17 -- typed letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Dmytriw, Olya (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Doktor, Paul (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1948-1966; 2 No year -- 8 autograph letters signed
        1953-1962 -- 5 typed letters signed
        1953-1959 -- 3 cards
      - Donaldson, Hildegarde (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Donnelley, Gaylord (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1964 Dec 30 -- typed letter signed
      - Donovan, Richard (Box 1, Folder 10)
        See: Yaddo; Yale; American Composers Alliance
      - Doran, Alexander A. (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1946 Dec 28 -- typed letter signed
      - Druian, Rafael (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1961-1964 -- 2 autograph letters signed
      - [Dukien, George W. ?] (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1950 Apr 7 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Durieux, Willem (Box 1, Folder 10)
        See: Durieux Chamber Ensemble
      - Edel, Oliver (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1949-1951 -- 2 typed letters signed (1-scrapbook)
      - Edmunds, John (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Edwards, Sidney (Box 1, Folder 10)
        See: Salzburg Quartet
      - Egerinsky, Leopold (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1947 Jul 20 -- autograph letter signed
      - Eisenstein, Phyllis (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1947 Jun 25 -- autograph letter signed
      - Elkus, Jonathan (Box 1, Folder 10)
        1959 Feb 25 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
        1959 Jan 26 -- typed letter signed
      - Elwell, Herbert (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1930; 1951 -- 2 autograph letters signed (1-scrapbook)
        1928; 1942 -- 2 typed letters signed (scrapbook)
      - Emerson, Gordon (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Engel, Lehman (Box 1, Folder 11)
        See: Arrow Music Press, Inc.
      - Epstein, Selma (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1962 Dec -- autograph letter signed
      - Ermili, Roger (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1965 Oct 2 -- autograph letter signed
      - Erstev, Betsy (Box 1, Folder 11)
        No year Jan 26 -- autograph letter signed (scrapbook)
      - Esty, Alice (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1961 -- 2 autograph letters signed
      - Etler, Alvin. (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1939 Oct 31; No date -- 2 autograph letters signed
      - Evarts, John (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1947 Dec 1 -- typed letter signed
      - Faden, Yarden (Box 1, Folder 11)
        [c.1964 Jan 12] -- autograph letter signed
      - Fahy, Mary-Louise (Box 1, Folder 11)
        1938 Sep 12 -- autograph letter signed
      - Fairbank, Janet (Box 1, Folder 11)
        No year Nov; No date -- 2 autograph letters signed